- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[folksy music]
[民谣音乐]
♪ ♪
- [struggling]
- [挣扎]
- [meows]
- [喵]
[both groan]
[两人都呻吟]
- Okay,
that's enough stretching.
- 好吧，
拉伸就足够了。
- [meow]
- [喵]
- Now we're ready
for a morning jog.
- 现在我们准备好了
晨跑。
- Meow!
- 喵！
- [heavy breathing]
- [粗重的呼吸]
Ahh!
[crash, thud]
啊！
[撞击声、重击声]
What's the matter, Gary?
Don't you like jogging?
怎么了，加里？
你不喜欢跑步吗？
- Meow, meow, meow.
- Oh, right. You're a snail.
- 喵，喵，喵。
- 哦，对了。你是一只蜗牛。
Hm. We've got to find
a way to get you moving.
嗯。我们必须找到
一种让你动起来的方法。
[banging]
[砰砰]
This should do it.
You'll "tank" me later.
这应该可以做到。
稍后你会“坦克”我。
[laughing]
[笑]
Hey, now you're moving.
嘿，现在你要搬家了。
- Meow, meow!
- Whoa--ow!
- 喵，喵！
- 哇哦！
I'm okay.
Ow!
我没事。
噢！
Ow!
Yow!
哟！
[groaning]
- [meowing]
[呻吟]
- [喵喵叫]
- Meow!
- 喵！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [pained moaning]
- [痛苦的呻吟]
Aww, poor Gary.
哇哦，可怜的加里。
Looks like you
could use a leg up.
看起来像你
可以用一条腿抬起来。
Or maybe two.
- [whimpers]
或者也许是两个。
- [呜咽]
[saw buzzing]
[看到嗡嗡声]
[grinding]
[研磨]
- There! A perfect set of legs.
- 那里！一双完美的腿。
Now let's make some for you.
现在让我们为您做一些。
This will only hurt
for a second.
这只会伤害
一会儿。
Yow!
哟！
- Meow!
- 喵！
Meow.
喵。
- Voilà.
- 瞧。
What do you think, Gary?
你觉得怎么样，加里？
- Me-ow, meow-meow.
- 喵呜，喵喵。
- Let's try 'em out.
- 让我们尝试一下。
Come on.
Come to SpongeBob.
快点。
来海绵宝宝吧
- Mm.
- 毫米。
- Oh, your first steps.
- Meow.
- 哦，你的第一步。
- 喵。
- My little guy's growing up.
- 我的小家伙长大了。
Now let's try something
a little harder.
现在让我们尝试一下
有点难。
[creaking]
[吱吱作响]
- Meow, meow, meow.
- 喵，喵，喵。
- Ooh, not bad.
Try this.
- 哦，还不错。
试试这个。
[Irish jig music]
[爱尔兰吉格音乐]
♪ ♪
- Meow, meow, meow, meooow!
- 喵，喵，喵，喵！
- Nice moves.
- 动作不错。
♪ ♪
Ow! Ah!
噢！啊!
[gasps] The student has
surpassed the master.
[喘气] 学生有
超越了大师。
Ready to stretch your stuff,
Gare-bear?
准备好伸展你的东西，
车站熊？
- Meow, meow.
Meow!
- 喵，喵。
喵！
- Hey, wait!
Whoa!
- 嘿，等等！
哇！
- Meow, meow.
- Oh! Oy.
- 喵，喵。
- 哦！哎哟。
After you.
- Meow, meow.
您先请。
- 喵，喵。
all: [gasping]
- Oh, yeah, that's right.
全体：[喘气]
- 哦，是的，没错。
You're not dreaming.
Check it out.
你不是在做梦。
一探究竟。
Snail with legs, people.
有腿的蜗牛，人们。
- Meow.
[growls flirtatiously]
- 喵。
- [purrs]
- [呼噜声]
- Would you look at that.
- 你能看一下吗？
- Well,
that's certainly different.
- 嗯，
这当然是不同的。
- [hisses]
- [嘶嘶声]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- Oh!
- 哦！
- [gasps] Gary!
- [喘气]加里！
- Hey, control your snail,
fella.
- 嘿，控制你的蜗牛，
伙计。
- Sorry. Guess Gary's new legs
got him a little excited.
- 对不起。猜猜加里的新腿
让他有点兴奋。
- [blows raspberry]
- [吹覆盆子]
- [hissing]
Pow!
- [嘶嘶声]
噗！
- You'll be hearing
from my lawyer!
- 你会听到
来自我的律师！
- What is your problem, man?
- [growling]
- 你有什么问题吗，伙计？
- [咆哮]
- Ah!
- 啊！
- Oh, wh--s--sorry!
- 噢，什——抱歉！
- Ah!
- His legs!
- 啊！
- 他的腿！
- Gary the snail,
that was very naughty.
- 蜗牛加里，
那是非常顽皮的。
- Meow.
- Oh. [laughing]
- 喵。
- 哦。 [笑]
I can't stay mad at you.
- Meow!
我不能一直生你的气。
- 喵！
- Whoa!
- 哇！
[exhausted moans]
[疲惫的呻吟声]
I'm a little beat, Gary.
我有点沮丧，加里。
Can you give me
a hand with the door?
你能给我吗
一只手拿着门？
- Meow-ow.
- 喵呜。
[struggling]
[挣扎]
- Looks like I should
give you a hand, huh?
- 看来我应该
帮你一把，嗯？
- Hm? Hm. Hmm.
- 嗯？嗯。唔。
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. Yow!
嗯嗯。
嗯嗯。哟！
They look a little tight
in the shoulder.
它们看起来有点紧
在肩膀上。
- Meow-meow,
meow-meow.
- 喵喵，
喵喵。
- Whoops! I accidentally
gave you two left hands.
- 哎呀！我一不小心
给了你两只左手。
Boop!
噗！
Perfect. Give 'em
a test drive, Gary.
完美的。给他们
试驾一下，加里。
- Meow, meow, meow...
- 喵，喵，喵……
[struggling]
[挣扎]
- Maybe you just
need some motivation.
-也许你只是
需要一些动力。
- Meow.
[grunting]
- 喵。
[咕噜声]
Meow!
喵！
- [yelps]
You're doing it, Gary.
- [尖叫声]
你正在做，加里。
Yes, yes!
Keep it up, keep it up!
是的，是的！
坚持下去，坚持下去！
Ow! Yes, yes!
- Meow!
噢！是的，是的！
- 喵！
- That's it, Gary.
Move the--move the--
- 就是这样，加里。
动一下——动一下——
Move those arms.
移动那些手臂。
- [giggling]
Meow-ow-ow-ow-ow-ow.
- [咯咯笑]
喵-喔-喔-喔-喔-喔。
Meow?
Meow.
喵？
喵。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [imitates a train]
- [模仿火车]
- [nonsensical whining]
- [无意义的抱怨]
- Meow.
- 喵。
[chewing noises]
[咀嚼声]
- One weekend
of pampering later.
- 一个周末
以后的宠爱。
- [sipping]
- [啜饮]
[ringing]
Ow!
[铃声]
噢！
Yikes! Look at the time!
I gotta get to the Krusty Krab.
哎呀！看看时间！
我得去蟹堡王店了
Thanks for spoiling me, Gary.
谢谢你宠我，加里。
I didn't have
to lift a "finger."
我没有
举起“手指”。
My fingers...
我的手指...
[groans] Wha--!
[呻吟] 什——！
A whole weekend of pampering
has left my limbs in limbo.
整个周末的呵护
让我的四肢陷入困境。
Got. To go. To work.
得到。去吧。去工作。
Hm?
嗯？
[dramatic piano music]
[戏剧性的钢琴音乐]
[struggling]
[挣扎]
Too weak to flip
Krabby Patties.
太弱了，无法翻转
蟹肉饼。
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Ooh.
Uh-oh.
- 哦。
呃哦。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[elastic stretching]
【弹性拉伸】
- Hm.
- 嗯。
Excuse me,
but I would like to complain!
对不起，
但我想投诉！
- I see. Well the Krusty Krab
takes customer feedback
- 我懂了。那么蟹堡王
接受客户反馈
very seriously, sir.
非常认真，先生。
After they pay
the $5 complaint fee.
他们付款后
5 美元的投诉费。
- All right, fine.
- 好吧，好吧。
- Yee-hee-hee-hee.
- 嘿嘿嘿嘿。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您，先生。
Now what seems to be
your problem?
现在看来是这样的
你的问题？
- There is slime on my patty.
- 我的肉饼上有粘液。
And mine has--[munching]
slime on it, too.
我的有--[咀嚼]
上面还有粘液。
- My patty doesn't
have enough slime! [laughing]
- 我的肉饼没有
有足够的史莱姆！ [笑]
- What?
Give me that.
- 什么？
给我那个。
Bleh! Ugh! Gah!
哎呀！啊!嘎！
SpongeBob! Just what do you
think you're doing
海绵宝宝！只是你做什么
认为你在做
changing me patty...formula?
改变我的小馅饼...配方？
- Meow. Meow-mow.
- 喵。喵喵。
- Squidward!
Why is there a mollusk
- 章鱼哥！
为什么有软体动物
cooking me Krabby Patties?
给我做蟹黄饼？
- I thought it was strangely
quiet and peaceful today.
- 我觉得这很奇怪
今天安静祥和。
- Where the halibut
is SpongeBob?
- 大比目鱼在哪里
是海绵宝宝吗？
- Maybe he quit?
Or got hit by a bus?!
- 也许他辞职了？
还是被公交车撞了？！
Or caught
a terminal disease!
或者被抓住
绝症！
- I don't care if he turned
into a bucket of chum.
- 我不在乎他是否转身
放入一桶密友中。
I need me fry cook!
我需要我炒菜！
Mr. Squidward,
you have the helm.
章鱼哥先生，
你掌舵。
- Attention Krusty Krab
customers: Get out.
- 注意蟹堡王
顾客：滚出去。
It's time for my break.
我的休息时间到了。
[irritated chatter]
[恼怒的喋喋不休]
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Are you okay in there?
你在里面还好吗？
You catch the flu or something?
你得了流感还是别的什么？
Ugh.
Are you at death's door?
啊。
你正濒临死亡之门吗？
Because you know darn well
they ain't
因为你非常了解
他们不是
valid excuses
to miss work!
有效的借口
错过工作！
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
- Ah! SpongeBob has gone
full raving loony.
- 啊！海绵宝宝走了
完全疯狂的疯子。
Uh-oh!
- Meow-meow-meow-meow
呃-哦！
- 喵喵喵喵
meow-meow-meow.
Meow-meow-meow-meow-meow-meow.
喵喵喵。
喵-喵-喵-喵-喵-喵。
- [purring]
- [咕噜声]
- [gasps, whirring]
- [喘气，呼呼]
What in the name
of Neptune's nostrils
名字里有什么
海王星的鼻孔
is going on in here?
这里发生什么事了？
SpongeBob, you're acting
like you're the pet
海绵宝宝，你演戏了
就像你是宠物一样
and that darn snail
is the owner.
还有那该死的蜗牛
是业主。
- Meow! Meow-meow-meow.
- 喵！喵喵喵。
- Bad snail.
Down boy.
- 坏蜗牛。
沮丧的男孩。
- [hissing]
- SpongeBob, what are you--
- [嘶嘶声]
- 海绵宝宝，你是什么——
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Snap out of it, SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝，振作起来！
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板？
- Have you completely
lost your mind, boy-o?
- 你完全
你疯了吗，小伙子？
Snails ain't supposed
to have arms and legs.
蜗牛不应该
有胳膊和腿。
- Aw, but Gary is so happy
with his new limbs.
- 哦，但是加里很高兴
和他的新四肢。
- [sighs happily]
- [高兴地叹气]
- Oh, is he?
- 哦，是吗？
Well it's time
to cut this nonsense.
是时候了
废话少说。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- Ay! [grunting]
- 哎呀！ [咕噜声]
- [hissing]
- [嘶嘶声]
- Huh-hah!
- 哈哈！
[snapping]
[啪啪啪]
- Meow.
- 喵。
- Mr. Krabs,
I'm sorry I forgot who I was.
- 蟹老板先生，
抱歉我忘记了我是谁。
- That's okay, boy-o.
- 没关系，小伙子。
- And Gary, I am so sorry
I tried to change you.
- 加里，我很抱歉
我试图改变你。
- [belches]
- [打嗝]
- And Patrick, I'm sorry I
haven't returned your hat yet.
- 帕特里克，我很抱歉
你的帽子还没归还。
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
It's okay...
没关系...
- Hm? Well, I guess I shouldn't
let these go to waste.
- 嗯？嗯，我想我不应该
让这些都浪费掉吧。
I can always use
an extra hand. [laughing]
我可以随时使用
额外的一手。 [笑]
- All right, all right.
That's enough Sponge-bobbery
- 好吧，好吧。
海绵宝宝就够了
for today, boy-o.
今天，小伙子。
Time to get you
flipping patties again.
是时候来接你了
再次翻转肉饼。
- Ah, sure is nice having
everything back to normal,
- 啊，当然很高兴拥有
一切恢复正常，
isn't it Gare-bear?
这不是加雷熊吗？
Yup.
Same old, same old.
是的。
老样子，老样子。
- Meow-ow.
- 喵呜。
[both sigh]
[两人叹气]
- Meow.
Meow.
- 喵。
喵。
- Oops! Sorry.
Boop-boop.
- 哎呀！对不起。
噗噗。
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪